hey everyone its Marella manelli and in
today's hair tutorial I'm gonna show you
four different foil placements and the
effects they create on the hair so stay
tuned and check it out to get started on
our highlights I went ahead and
sectioned this mannequin into four
quadrants so right down the middle and
then from ear to ear creating four
sections this bottom section right down
here from the occipital down I went
ahead and braided it because we're not
gonna be doing any highlights on it so
this is just gonna give me a nice
controlled clean area to work with so
this doesn't get in the way this video
is all about placements and the effects
that they can cause in the placement of
the highlights so for example I'm gonna
be doing horizontal sections right in
through here and then vertical sections
and then for the front two sections
we're gonna be doing a diagonal forward
and diagonal back for this project I'm
using Kenner professionals simply blonde
blue powder Lightner at a 1-2-3 mixing
ratio with 30 volume developer this is
typically my go-to Lightner for all
highlights but of course you're gonna
want to customize your Lightner to your
client's needs for the purpose of
showing you the four different
placements and the effects they create
I'm gonna be taking slices in each of
the sections for this first quadrant I'm
going to show you horizontal sections
with slices you will see that this is
going to create lots of diffusion
horizontal highlights are great for
general highlighting overall brightness
high diffusion natural-looking
highlights and color correction remember
that horizontal placement is going to
create the illusion of fullness and
weight in your color so if you are
working with heavily layered hair you
will see a line of demarcation where the
highlight ends it's important for you to
note each of the subsections you are
creating while doing highlights for
demonstration purposes I am taking half
inch sections in between my foils if you
want to create lots of Blondin blending
and brightness you will want to take
smaller subsections
if you want to create a very natural
effect or higher contrast with a deeper
background for more depth wider
subsections are essential in addition to
subsections and placement how you apply
your highlight is going to make a
difference as well so for example if you
go in with baby lights a chunky
highlight or even a teasing light you'll
create different effects but you're
still creating fullness weight and
diffusion with the placement so keep
this in mind as you were learning
different placements in this video and
how you should customize your placement
and application for each client on the
Left quadrant on creating vertical
highlights these can sometimes be
challenging to apply however they create
stunning ribbon effects in the hair and
give the illusion of link I'm still
taking slices in this quadrant so you
can see the full effect of the placement
however just like I mentioned in the
horizontal segment the type of technique
used in the placement will vary for your
end result vertical placement is used
and great for creating high contrast
diffusing the stopping point of your
highlights when working with heavily
layered hair and giving the illusion of
longer looking hair some tips when
applying vertical highlights is work in
small sections for maximum control
tension is key for holding your foil in
place while applying and choose the side
that you feel most comfortable working
on first since all of your foils will be
laying in the same direction while you
are applying and one last thing is have
lots of duckbills
on hand to help you hold your foils in
place just remember that when applying
vertical foils you're creating the
maximum amount of contrast for the front
quadrants I will be doing the same
diagonal placement except that in the
front left quadrant I'm applying
diagonal forward sections and on the
other side they are diagonal back this
placement will create two effects
depending on how your client wears her
hair whether it's towards her face or
away from her face
you will either create high contrast
with diffusion which means you will see
a difference between the highlights and
the depth but the line of where they
start will be softer than with the
vertical highlights or you will create
diffusion with soft contrast depending
on how the slice veils over since this
placement lives between vertical and
horizontal you are getting the best of
both worlds however the direction of
forward or back fall is very important
on how your client wears her hair and
what end result you want for example if
your client wears her hair towards her
face diagonal forward will create more
diffusion than placing them diagonal
back you will see the difference in each
of these placements once the hair is
finished and styled and here's the final
result on the different boiling
placements and the effects that they
create so let's go ahead and recap what
we did on this mannequin head so on this
side over here this is a pretty typical
horizontal foil placement you have lots
of blondie and lots of blending so
overall it looks rather blond so I see a
lot of stylists do this technique and we
kind of know what it creates you can see
this would be if somebody wanted a nice
overall blondie effect now in this
section over here we did more of a
vertical placement so in this section
you can really almost kind of see these
really defined highlights really
creating more of a ribbon effect so when
you go in and curl this let's go ahead
and take a piece out you can really see
almost kind of like a chunk if that
makes sense
so we were to go in and really create a
really tight curl we're gonna have this
long pop of blonde poking through just
like a ribbon would show on the hair now
on the right side of her head we went in
with diagonal back sections so this
actually gives a really nice blended
effect if you're gonna wear the hair
towards the face but look what happens
when we bring this back you can really
see these stripes of blonde because we
went in in this fashion now of course
this can change depending on the type of
highlight you put in so keep in mind we
did put in slices but this gave a really
nice blended effect going diagonal back
and for the opposite side of her head we
went in with diagonal forward sections
so we took the sections going in this
direction so what this created is lots
of pop of blonde almost similar to
ribbon effect with the vertical
highlights created but with a much more
blended version of the vertical
highlights so what you can see is if she
what she wears her hair forward what
this is going to create is nice ribbons
of blonde with lots of contrast versus
the other side had much more blended
effect so you can really kind of take
these two different techniques here
towards the front and really customize
it depending on how your client wears
her hair whether it's forward or away
from her face or if she wants a blended
effect or lots of contrast so I really
hoped you enjoyed this hair tutorial and
I hope you learned something new and if
you did I would love to know what it is
so subscribe like and comment down below
and let me know which technique is your
favorite so until next time